
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Market News</title><link>http://www.canadianbusiness.com</link><description>News, opinion and community for business leaders, entrepreneurs and investors.</description><language>en-us</language><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 20:15:15 -0400</pubDate><item><title>Maple Leaf complies with disgruntled shareholder request for vote on changes</title><link>http://www.canadianbusiness.com/markets/headline_news/article.jsp?content=b5486554</link><description><![CDATA[TORONTO - Maple Leaf Foods Inc. (TSX:MFI) will comply with a request from disgruntled shareholder West Face Capital to hold a vote on the activist]]></description><author>Sunny Freeman, The Canadian Press</author><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 20:12:00 -0400</pubDate><guid></guid><category>Market News</category><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>TORONTO - Maple Leaf Foods Inc. (TSX:MFI) will comply with a request from disgruntled shareholder West Face Capital to hold a vote on the activist hedge fund's proposals to revamp it's board, but it will not call a special meeting to do so.</p><p>The meat processing and bakery company announced Thursday that it will hold a non-binding vote on five proposals aimed at shaking up the board of directors at a scheduled meeting April 28 in Toronto.</p><p>West Face, which owns an 11.4 per cent stake in Maple Leaf is unhappy with the makeup of the current board, which recently authorized a billion-dollar plan to reorganize the company hard hit by a deadly Listeria outbreak at one of its plants in 2008 and the impact of a rising loonie.</p><p>West Face wants to give shareholders a chance to vote on whether some board members are independent enough from the McCain family, which holds a controlling stake, as well as motions to reduce the board to nine members from the current 12 and adopt a "say-on-pay" policy.</p><p>Maple Leaf said earlier in the week that it has begun a process to revamp its board of directors and has formed a committee of its board to solicit shareholder input as it searches for new director candidates after two representatives from one of its largest shareholders stepped down this fall.</p><p>"Recent changes in the composition of our board, and in our shareholder base, require changes to the board," said James Hankinson, chairman of a recently established shareholder relations committee.</p><p>"The shareholder relations committee is actively seeking input on the board renewal process from Maple Leaf shareholders and we expect to provide a substantive update on our progress prior to the annual and special meeting. This will enable shareholders to make an informed vote on the West Face Capital resolutions," he said in a statement.</p><p>Maple Leaf said it chose to hold the vote at its annual meeting rather than at a separate meeting to give shareholders the chance to consider the proposals in the context of a "board renewal process" and the election of directors.</p><p>It said it would also be too costly to hold two separate meetings.</p><p>But West Face responded late Thursday that the company's decision to hold the vote at a pre-scheduled meeting leaves shareholders no time to offer feedback before the board is elected in a routine process at annual general meetings.</p><p>"Once again, the board is showing its disrespect for shareholders other than McCain Capital by delaying the special meeting so that advisory resolutions on the constitution of the board cannot be considered before the board asks for a vote on its own election," said John Lute, a spokesman for the hedge fund.</p><p>"The board has simply ignored calls for shareholders to have a say in how their board is nominated before they have to vote."</p><p>West Face has complained that the Maple Leaf board is too big and alleges some of the directors are too closely involved on a personal level with the McCain family.</p><p>That prompted the Toronto-based food and bakery company's latest move is a regulatory filing that defends the independence of the company's lead director, Purdy Crawford, earlier this month.</p><p>The move by West Face follows a major shakeup in ownership of Maple Leaf stock last week when the Ontario Teachers Pension Plan Board decided to sell its entire 25 per cent stake in Maple Leaf at a discount.</p><p>It was no secret that Teachers was rethinking its holdings in Maple Leaf Foods _ a company that it had backed since it joined the family of Wallace McCain to buy the company in 1995.</p><p>The pension plan announced in July 2009 that it had notified McCain Capital Corp. that it would terminate the agreement between the family company and Teachers, effective at the end of June 2010.</p><p>Teachers sold a 10 per cent stake to West Face in August, also at a significant discount after two of its representatives on the board stepped down after a dispute over board room minutes that it said did not accurately reflect that its approval of a billion dollar restructuring plan was conditional.</p><p>Under the plan, the company aims to reduce costs and improve profit as it grapples with weaker sales, rising raw material prices and a high Canadian dollar, which makes its exports more expensive to foreign buyers.</p><p>For its part, the company has maintained there's no problem at the board level and that the proxy battle is "a costly and unnecessary process" and a distraction from its attempts to raise the $1.3 billion it needs to restructure.</p><p>Maple Leaf has already embarked on plans to shut down and consolidate its 24 processed meat operations which could leave hundreds of employees jobless but improve profitability.</p><p>Maple Leaf, which is also Canada's largest baker through its Canada Bread subsidiary, employs about 23,500 people at operations across Canada, the U.S., the U.K. and Asia.</p><p>Its well-known brands include Maple Leaf and Burns cold cuts and Dempsters breads. The company was formed in the early 1990s from the merger of meat processor Canada Packers and baker Maple Leaf Mills.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Final Wall Street figures: Dow up 14.00 to close at 11,573.49</title><link>http://www.canadianbusiness.com/markets/headline_news/article.jsp?content=c5486768</link><description><![CDATA[Dow Jones IndustrialsHigh: 11,580.84Low: 11,542.62Close: 11,573.49Change: +14.00Other IndexesStandard&amp;Poors 500 Index: 1256.77 &#x2014;2.07NYSE Index: 7925.36 &#x2014;6.40Nasdaq Composite Index: 2665.60 &#x2014;5.88AMEX Composite Index: 2170.18 +6.46Russell 2000 Index:]]></description><author>The Associated Press</author><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 17:35:00 -0400</pubDate><guid></guid><category>Market News</category><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dow Jones Industrials</p><p>High: 11,580.84</p><p>Low: 11,542.62</p><p>Close: 11,573.49</p><p>Change: +14.00</p><p>Other Indexes</p><p>Standard&amp;Poors 500 Index: 1256.77 &#x2014;2.07</p><p>NYSE Index: 7925.36 &#x2014;6.40</p><p>Nasdaq Composite Index: 2665.60 &#x2014;5.88</p><p>AMEX Composite Index: 2170.18 +6.46</p><p>Russell 2000 Index: 788.96 &#x2014;1.63</p><p>DJ U.S. TotalStkMkt: 13,282.52 &#x2014;23.24</p><p>Volume</p><p>NYSE consolidated volume: 2,579,566,339</p><p>Total number of issues traded: 3,127</p><p>Issues higher in price: 1,449</p><p>Issues lower in price: 1,561</p><p>Issues unchanged: 117</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Fewer Americans apply for unemployment benefits and consumers spend more</title><link>http://www.canadianbusiness.com/markets/headline_news/article.jsp?content=b5483038</link><description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON - Economic reports suggest American employers are laying off fewer workers, businesses are ordering more computers and appliances, and consumers are spending with more]]></description><author>Christopher S. Rugaber, The Associated P</author><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 17:25:00 -0400</pubDate><guid></guid><category>Market News</category><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>WASHINGTON - Economic reports suggest American employers are laying off fewer workers, businesses are ordering more computers and appliances, and consumers are spending with more confidence. Combined, the data confirm the economy is improving, and further job gains are expected in 2011.</p><p>The economy's outlook is brightening even though hiring has yet to strengthen enough to reduce an unemployment rate near 10 per cent.</p><p>The number of people applying for unemployment benefits fell last week to a seasonally adjusted 420,000, the Labour Department said Thursday. That's the second-lowest level since July 2008.</p><p>Applications have fallen below 425,000 in four of the past five weeks &#x2014; a significant improvement after hovering most of the year above 450,000.</p><p>But the unemployment rate rose in November to 9.8 per cent. And employers added only 39,000 net new jobs.</p><p>The economy needs to generate more than 200,000 jobs a month consistently to make a dent in the unemployment rate. And applications for unemployment benefits need to fall to 375,000 or below before job gains are likely to get to that level, economists say. Applications peaked during the recession at 651,000 in March 2009.</p><p>Even when claims do fall to those levels, the unemployment rate will likely remain high. With 15 million people out of work, it will take years to gain enough jobs to bring unemployment back to a more normal level of around 5.5 per cent.</p><p>"Don't forget how many people lost their jobs," said Tom Porcelli, an economist at RBC Capital Markets, a reference to the more than 7.3 million laid off during the worst recession since the Great Depression. "The unemployment rate is still going to remain high because of all the people out of work."</p><p>As of last month, more than 6.3 million people have been of work for six months or more, making up nearly 42 per cent of the unemployed. That's near a record high of 6.76 million set in May.</p><p>And those out of work for long periods will find it particularly hard to get back to work, Porcelli said. Employers are less likely to hire the long-term unemployed, in part because many workers' skills deteriorate the longer they are out of work.</p><p>Despite months of sluggish hiring, the economy is headed in the right direction. Consumers spent more for the fifth straight month in November, the Commerce Department said. Their incomes rose, too. That was because of stock gains &#x2014; not pay increases. But any spending increase is a sign of greater confidence in the economy. Affluent shoppers, whose spending carries outsize impact, are spending especially freely.</p><p>U.S. businesses, sitting on nearly $2 trillion in cash, are parting with a bit more of it. Companies increased their orders for long-lasting manufactured products, excluding volatile transportation goods, by the sharpest amount in eight months in November. Demand rose for computers, appliances and heavy machinery.</p><p>Both consumers and businesses are likely to spend more in the new year now that President Barack Obama has signed a broad package of tax cuts into law. Consumers can bank on a 2 per cent cut in payroll taxes. That's another $2,000 a year to a person earning $100,000 a year.</p><p>The tax package also gives companies a break if they buy big machinery and other capital goods next year. That will likely spur more business investment, and could lead to more jobs.</p><p>"You need someone to operate the new equipment," said Jennifer Lee, an economist at BMO Capital Markets. "Businesses are running their work forces flat out already."</p><p>But the economy faces many challenges that could slow the current momentum.</p><p>Housing remains a major weight. In November, people bought new homes at a seasonally adjusted annual rate of 290,000 units, the government said. That's less than half the rate that economists consider healthy. And it's barely above the weakest pace in 47 years.</p><p>The market for previously owned homes is also struggling. Those are selling at the slowest pace in 13 years.</p><p>Meagre home sales, along with millions of foreclosures, could dampen home prices further. That would make consumers feel poorer and possibly spend less, restraining economic growth.</p><p>Rising oil prices might also hurt the economy. On Thursday, prices rose above $91 a barrel &#x2014; the highest point in two years. Gas prices have also jumped. That takes money from consumers that they would otherwise use to buy other goods.</p><p>And unemployment is likely to remain painfully high for all of next year. Most economists expect it to be near 9 per cent by the end of 2011.</p><p>The number of people receiving unemployment benefits dropped 103,000 to little more than 4 million in the week ending Dec. 11, the government said. That doesn't include millions of additional laid-off workers who are receiving emergency aid under extended unemployment benefits programs set up during the recession. About 4.7 million people are receiving extended benefits for up to 99 weeks.</p><p>All told, about 8.9 million people obtained unemployment benefits during the week of Dec. 4, according to the latest data available. That was about 300,000 fewer people than in the previous week.</p><p>___</p><p>AP Economics Writers Jeannine Aversa and Martin Crutsinger contributed to this report.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Most actively traded companies on the TSX, TSX Venture Exchange markets</title><link>http://www.canadianbusiness.com/markets/headline_news/article.jsp?content=b5486628</link><description><![CDATA[TORONTO - Some of the most active companies traded Thursday on the Toronto Stock Exchange and the TSX Venture Exchange:Toronto Stock Exchange (13,371.2 down 9.5]]></description><author>The Canadian Press</author><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 17:16:00 -0400</pubDate><guid></guid><category>Market News</category><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>TORONTO - Some of the most active companies traded Thursday on the Toronto Stock Exchange and the TSX Venture Exchange:</p><p>Toronto Stock Exchange (13,371.2 down 9.5 points):</p><p>Jura Energy Corp. (TSX:JEC). Oil and gas. Up one cent, or 28.57 per cent, at 4.5 cents on 9,510,024 shares. Jura has been advised that the TSX has completed its review of the company and determined it meets the exchange's requirements for continued listing.</p><p>MagIndustries Corp. (TSX:MAA). Natural resources. Down 1.5 cents, or 5.66 per cent, at 25 cents on 7,431,344 shares.</p><p>Cline Mining Corp. (TSX:CMK). Mining. Up 60 cents, or 20.55 per cent, at $3.52 on 6,506,459 shares.</p><p>Avcorp Industries Inc. (TSX:AVP). Airframe manufacturer. Down half a cent, or 33.33 per cent, at 10 cents on 6,341,015 shares.</p><p>High Arctic Energy Services Inc. (TSX:HWO). Oilfield services. Up two cents, or 10 per cent, at 22 cents on 5,995,275 shares.</p><p>Manulife Financial Corp. (TSX:MFC). Insurance. Down 20 cents, or 1.15 per cent, at $17.21 on 5,712,408 shares.</p><p>TSX Venture Exchange (2,175.36 up 8.02 points):</p><p>Transeuro Energy Corp. (TSXV:TSU). Oil and gas. Up three cents, or 35.29 per cent, at 11.5 cents on 7,030,975 shares. The Vancouver-based company says it intends to proceed with a non-brokered private placement to raise gross proceeds of up to $2 million to be used primarily for Ukraine drilling operations.</p><p>Alexander Nubia International Inc. (TSXV:AAN). Mining. Up three cents, or 13.04 per cent, at 26 cents on 6,593,350 shares.</p><p>Companies reporting major news:</p><p>Air Canada (TSX:AC.B). Airline. Down five cents, or 1.38 per cent, at $3.58 on 757,263 shares. The Globe and Mail reported that Canada's largest airline could face higher financing costs if an new OECD plan governing export financing on commercial aircraft goes into effect before it arranges financing for an order of new Boeing 787s.</p><p>Davis + Henderson Income Fund (TSX:DHF.UN). Down 12 cents, or 0.59 per cent, at $20.12 on 123,057 units. The company has purchased repossession management company Asset Inc. for $76 million in cash.</p><p>Ventana Gold Corp. (TSX:VEN). Mining. Up 23 cents, or 1.76 per cent, at $13.28 on 1,206,614 shares. The board of the Vancouver-mineral explorer recommended that shareholders reject a $1.5-billion takeover offer by Brazilian resource company Grupo EBX because it is "inadequate" and "not in the best interests of Ventana or its shareholders." The takeover offer stands at $12.63 per share.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ventana Gold board suggests shareholders reject takeover offer by Grupo EBX</title><link>http://www.canadianbusiness.com/markets/headline_news/article.jsp?content=b5484779</link><description><![CDATA[VANCOUVER - Ventana Gold Corp. (TSX:VEN) says its board of directors has recommended that shareholders reject a $1.5-billion takeover offer by Brazilian resource company Grupo]]></description><author>The Canadian Press</author><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 17:03:00 -0400</pubDate><guid></guid><category>Market News</category><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>VANCOUVER - Ventana Gold Corp. (TSX:VEN) says its board of directors has recommended that shareholders reject a $1.5-billion takeover offer by Brazilian resource company Grupo EBX because it undervalues the company.</p><p>Ventana added that it has adopted a "limited-duration'' shareholder rights plan as it attempts to negotiate an alternative to the unsolicited offer by Brazilian billionaire Eike Batista.</p><p>AUX Canada Acquisition Inc., formed by EBX to acquire Ventana, had offered to buy all outstanding shares it doesn't already own for $12.63 apiece.</p><p>The EBX offer, which expires Jan. 24, is a premium of 26 per cent to Ventana's closing price Nov. 26. However, it is well below Ventana's closing price of $13.28 on Thursday.</p><p>Vancouver-based Ventana said the vote to reject the offer was unanimous and that it believed the offer undervalues Ventana and its Bodega gold project in Colombia.</p><p>"The board thoroughly reviewed the formal offer documents in connection with AUX's unsolicited offer and concluded that the offer is inadequate and is not in the best interests of Ventana or its shareholders," chairman Richard Warke said in a statement.</p><p>Under its shareholders' rights plan, current shareholders could be entitled to buy more shares at "a substantial discount," the statement said.</p><p>The rights plan expires at 5 p.m. Pacific time Jan. 31, and is intended to ensure that "in the context of the unsolicited takeover proposal'' the Ventana board has "sufficient time to identify, develop and negotiate alternatives to maximize shareholder value.''</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Former American Airlines CEO Donald Carty joining CN board of directors</title><link>http://www.canadianbusiness.com/markets/headline_news/article.jsp?content=b5486456</link><description><![CDATA[MONTREAL - Former American Airlines chief executive Donald Carty is joining the board of Canadian National Railway Co. (TSX:CNR).Carty, who also is the retired vice-chairman]]></description><author>The Canadian Press</author><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 16:58:00 -0400</pubDate><guid></guid><category>Market News</category><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>MONTREAL - Former American Airlines chief executive Donald Carty is joining the board of Canadian National Railway Co. (TSX:CNR).</p><p>Carty, who also is the retired vice-chairman and chief financial officer of Dell Inc., will join the board on Jan. 1.</p><p>He is currently chairman of Virgin America Airlines, Inc. and Porter Airlines, Inc. and serves as a director of a number of companies including Barrick Gold (TSX:ABX), Talisman Energy (TSX:TLM) and Dell.</p><p>CN, with more than 21,000 workers in Canada and the United States, operates the largest rail network in Canada.</p><p>Shares in the company were down 63 cents at $66.63 on the Toronto Stock Exchange on Thursday.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Canada Bond yields and prime rates for Thursday, Dec. 23, 2010</title><link>http://www.canadianbusiness.com/markets/headline_news/article.jsp?content=c5486430</link><description><![CDATA[TORONTO - Canada Bond yields (previous day in brackets):Two-year: 1.69% (1.66)Five-year: 2.46% (2.43)10-year: 3.18% (3.17)30-year: 3.57% (3.56)Interest rates:Prime rate: 3.00%Overnight lending rate: 1.00%]]></description><author>The Canadian Press</author><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 16:46:00 -0400</pubDate><guid></guid><category>Market News</category><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>TORONTO - Canada Bond yields (previous day in brackets):</p><p>Two-year: 1.69% (1.66)</p><p>Five-year: 2.46% (2.43)</p><p>10-year: 3.18% (3.17)</p><p>30-year: 3.57% (3.56)</p><p>Interest rates:</p><p>Prime rate: 3.00%</p><p>Overnight lending rate: 1.00%</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Gold miner Randgold says Ivory Coast violence will hit fourth-quarter production</title><link>http://www.canadianbusiness.com/markets/headline_news/article.jsp?content=b5486414</link><description><![CDATA[LONDON - Gold mining company Randgold Resources Ltd. says instability in Ivory Coast will hit its fourth-quarter production.Randgold said Thursday its Tongon mine, in northern]]></description><author>The Associated Press</author><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 16:43:00 -0400</pubDate><guid></guid><category>Market News</category><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>LONDON - Gold mining company Randgold Resources Ltd. says instability in Ivory Coast will hit its fourth-quarter production.</p><p>Randgold said Thursday its Tongon mine, in northern Ivory Coast, has curtailed operations. The West African nation's political crisis has held up the start of the second stream by blocking supply routes and causing shipping delays that have prevented delivery of key components. Tongon is now expected to produce 35,000 ounces this year.</p><p>Chief executive Mark Bristow said the fourth quarter of 2010 was proving even tougher than anticipated.</p><p>The United Nations says at least 173 people have died in violence over Ivory Coast's disputed presidential election. Ivory Coast was once an economic hub as the world's top cocoa producer.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>TSX Venture Exchange closed 8.02 points higher at 2,175.36 on Thursday</title><link>http://www.canadianbusiness.com/markets/headline_news/article.jsp?content=c5486401</link><description><![CDATA[TORONTO - The TSX Venture Exchange closed Thursday at 2,175.36, up 8.02 points. The volume was 334.5 million shares.]]></description><author>The Canadian Press</author><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 16:41:00 -0400</pubDate><guid></guid><category>Market News</category><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>TORONTO - The TSX Venture Exchange closed Thursday at 2,175.36, up 8.02 points. The volume was 334.5 million shares.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>TSX lower as mining stocks lose ground, economic growth misses expectations</title><link>http://www.canadianbusiness.com/markets/headline_news/article.jsp?content=b5482931</link><description><![CDATA[TORONTO - The Toronto stock market closed slightly lower Thursday, with  mining stocks and copper prices backing off as investors took in the latest]]></description><author>Malcolm Morrison, The Canadian Press</author><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 16:40:00 -0400</pubDate><guid></guid><category>Market News</category><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>TORONTO - The Toronto stock market closed slightly lower Thursday, with  mining stocks and copper prices backing off as investors took in the latest reading on the Canadian economy, which missed expectations.</p><p>The S&amp;P/TSX composite index closed 9.5 points lower at 13,371.2 while the TSX Venture Exchange rose 8.02 points to 2,175.36.</p><p>The Canadian dollar was higher against the U.S. currency, up 0.52 of a cent at 99.12 cents US as Statistics Canada said that gross domestic product increased 0.2 per cent in October following a 0.1 per cent decline in September. The agency said mining and oil and gas extraction were the main source of growth.</p><p>But the showing was less than the 0.3 per cent rise that economists had expected as manufacturing decreased 0.6 per cent.</p><p>"October&#x2019;s result, combined with the weak hand-off to Q4 from September, suggest that growth in the final quarter of the year will be held to a maximum rate of two to 2.5 per cent on an annualized basis," said TD Economics economist Francis Fong.</p><p>Manufacturers of non-durable goods cut back production by 2.3 per cent while those of durable goods increased their output by 0.8 per cent as production of motor vehicles and associated parts increased.</p><p>Gold stocks ran ahead even as bullion moved lower with the February contract on the New York Mercantile Exchange down $6.90 to US$1,380.50 an ounce. Goldcorp Inc. (TSX:G) shed 20 cents to C$45.19.</p><p>The energy sector was slightly higher as the February crude contract on the Nymex gained $1.03 to US$91.51 a barrel, a day after crude closed above US$90 a barrel for the first time since October 2008. Talisman Energy (TSX:TLM) lost 14 cents to C$22.</p><p>Metal prices were soft with the March copper contract on the New York Mercantile Exchange down two cents at US$4.26 a pound after hitting a record closing high earlier in the week. The base metals sector was off 0.5 per cent with Equinox Minerals (TSX:EQN) falling 10 cents to C$6 while First Quantum (TSX:FM) was down $2.65 at $108.99.</p><p>Financials were weak as Bank of Montreal (TSX:BMO) moved down 80 cents to $57.05 while Manulife Financial (TSX:MFC) lost 20 cents to $17.21.</p><p>The tepid showing across most sectors comes at the end of a rewarding year on the Toronto market, which is up about 13 per cent for 2010, led by strong gains in mining stocks.</p><p>"In 2010, the trend is definitely up...people have made money," said Pat McHugh, senior portfolio manager at Manulife Asset Management.</p><p>"We&#x2019;re experiencing a nice Santa Claus rally right now, the market is basically saying that things are improving, no one is talking about a double dip recession or anything else anymore and thank goodness for that."</p><p>U.S. markets were little changed as investors took in a mixed bag of economic data.</p><p>Orders for durable goods declined by a larger than expected 1.3 per cent in November, led by transportation equipment orders. Economists had expected a dip of 0.5 per cent. But the U.S. Commerce Department reported that excluding transportation, durable goods orders rose by 2.4 per cent.</p><p>The U.S. government also reported that consumers increased  spending 0.4 per cent in November. The gain came after shoppers ratcheted up spending by 0.7 per cent in October, the most since August 2009.</p><p>And slightly fewer people applied for unemployment benefits last week, the second drop in three weeks and a sign the job market is slowly healing. The U.S. Labour Department said the number of people seeking benefits edged down by 3,000 to a seasonally adjusted 420,000 in the week that ended Dec. 18.</p><p>New York's Dow Jones industrial average gained 14 points to 11,573.49.</p><p>The Nasdaq composite index declined 5.88 points to 2,665.6 while the S&amp;P 500 index lost 2.07 points to 1,256.77.</p><p>With Thursday's economic data out of the way, traders will be preparing for the Christmas break. The TSX closes at 1 p.m. EST on Friday while markets in the U.S. and Germany are closed. British and French bourses are also open for half a day.</p><p>In corporate news, Danish container shipping and oil group A.P. Moller-Maersk A/S has acquired Brazilian oil group SK do Brasil Ltda. from SK Energy Co. Ltd. for US$2.4 billion in cash on a debt-free basis. Moller-Maersk says the acquisition gives its oil unit access to "immediate production and significant growth potential" offshore Brazil and will help replace its oil reserves in the long term.</p><p>Air Canada (TSX:AC.B) shares were down five cents at $3.58 after the Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development announced new rules governing export financing for the purchase of commercial aircraft.</p><p>A provision of the agreement allows some previously ordered aircraft to be covered by existing financing terms. The Globe and Mail reported Wednesday that Air Canada (TSX:AC.A) could face higher financing costs if the OECD plan goes into effect before the airline arranges financing for an order of new Boeing 787s.</p><p>Davis + Henderson Income Fund (TSX:DHF.UN) has bought repossession management company Asset Inc. for $76 million in cash. Asset provides insolvency and repossession management to creditors of movable property like cars and boats. Davis + Henderson units were off 12 cents at $20.12.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Oil rises to above US$91 a barrel on positive U.S. economic reports</title><link>http://www.canadianbusiness.com/markets/headline_news/article.jsp?content=b5482204</link><description><![CDATA[NEW YORK, N.Y. - Optimistic economic news helped push the price of oil above US$91 a barrel on Thursday &#x2014; the highest it's been in]]></description><author>The Associated Press</author><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 16:39:00 -0400</pubDate><guid></guid><category>Market News</category><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>NEW YORK, N.Y. - Optimistic economic news helped push the price of oil above US$91 a barrel on Thursday &#x2014; the highest it's been in more than two years.</p><p>Benchmark crude for February delivery rose $1.03 to settle at $91.51 on the New York Mercantile Exchange.</p><p>Most analysts say oil prices have been rising not because of strong demand and dwindling supplies, but on hopes that an improving economy usually means more demand for oil and gas</p><p>The U.S. Commerce Department said that consumers spent more in November than the month before. And the U.S. Labour Department said that the number of Americans applying for unemployment benefits for the first time fell by 3,000 last week to 420,000.</p><p>A weaker U.S. dollar also supported higher oil prices. Since oil is priced in U.S. dollars, it becomes more affordable to investors with foreign currency like the euro as the U.S. dollar falls.</p><p>The PortiaGroup-OSIP study says higher gas pump prices are taking a bigger bite out of U.S. household spending: an average 7.4 per cent of median household income compared with 6.5 per cent last year and 4.2 per cent in 2008. If the pattern of higher oil prices persists, the average share of income spent on gasoline could rise to almost 10 per cent by spring, with pump prices around $3.75 or more a gallon.</p><p>While oil and gasoline prices are climbing, the price of one of the main heating sources in the U.S. &#x2014; natural gas &#x2014; is falling. It's down about 11 per cent in the past two weeks. On Thursday natural gas lost 6.9 cents to settle at $4.083 per 1,000 cubic feet on the Nymex.</p><p>Much of the United States has shivered through below-average temperatures in December, and on Thursday the Energy Department said the U.S. natural gas supplies shrank last week by 184 billion cubic feet. But there is so much natural gas in storage &#x2014; almost three and a half trillion cubic feet, or more than eight per cent more than the five-year average &#x2014; that prices have stayed relatively low.</p><p>Some weather forecasters think winter's icy grip will ease next month, which could keep natural gas prices down. "Slightly decreased heating demand in January is expected along a large swath of the country from Texas through the Mid-Atlantic region and north into New York and New England," said Chris Kostas, senior power and gas analyst with consultants Energy Security Analysis Inc. "The softer-than-normal power demand should also reduce gas demand for power generation along the East Coast in January," Kostas added.</p><p>Natural gas is used to generate about 20 per cent of the nation's electricity.</p><p>In other Nymex trading, heating oil rose 1.23 cents to settle at $2.5408 per gallon and gasoline gained 1.81 cents to settle at $2.4426 per gallon.</p><p>In London, Brent crude rose 60 cents to settle at $94.25 on the ICE Futures exchange.</p><p>(TSX:ECA, TSX:IMO, TSX:SU, TSX:HSE, NYSE:BP, NYSE:COP, NYSE:XOM, NYSE:CVX, TSX:CNQ, TSX:TLM, TSX:COS.UN, TSX:CVE)</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Financial market highlights: TSX closed  down 9.50 points to 13,371.20</title><link>http://www.canadianbusiness.com/markets/headline_news/article.jsp?content=c5486300</link><description><![CDATA[TORONTO - Highlights at the close of Thursday's world financial market trading.Stocks:S&amp;P/TSX Composite Index &#x2014; 13,371.20 down 9.50 pointsTSX Venture Exchange &#x2014; 2,175.36 up 8.02]]></description><author>The Canadian Press</author><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 16:29:00 -0400</pubDate><guid></guid><category>Market News</category><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>TORONTO - Highlights at the close of Thursday's world financial market trading.</p><p>Stocks:</p><p>S&amp;P/TSX Composite Index &#x2014; 13,371.20 down 9.50 points</p><p>TSX Venture Exchange &#x2014; 2,175.36 up 8.02 points</p><p>TSX60 &#x2014; 763.87 down 0.79 points</p><p>Dow &#x2014; 11,573.49 up 14.00 points</p><p>S&amp;P 500 &#x2014; 1,256.77 down 2.07 points</p><p>Nasdaq &#x2014; 2,665.60 down 5.88 points</p><p>Nasdaq Canada &#x2014; 750.33 up 1.45 points</p><p>Oil futures:</p><p>Light, sweet crude: US$91.51 up $1.03</p><p>(February contract)</p><p>Cdn _ 99.12 cents US, up 0.52 of a cent</p><p>Pound _ C$1.5567, down 0.40 of a cent</p><p>Euro _ C$1.3338, up 0.53 of a cent</p><p>Euro _ US$1.3120, up 0.21 of a cent</p><p>Gold:</p><p>New York &#x2014; US$1,380.50 down $6.90</p><p>(February contract)</p><p>Prices not available.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Rising oil helps push loonie higher, economic growth misses expectations</title><link>http://www.canadianbusiness.com/markets/headline_news/article.jsp?content=b5483122</link><description><![CDATA[TORONTO - The loonie closed higher against the U.S. dollar Thursday despite data showing a sub-par performance by the Canadian economy in October while copper]]></description><author>Malcolm Morrison, The Canadian Press</author><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 16:28:00 -0400</pubDate><guid></guid><category>Market News</category><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>TORONTO - The loonie closed higher against the U.S. dollar Thursday despite data showing a sub-par performance by the Canadian economy in October while copper prices fell back from recent highs.</p><p>The Canadian dollar added 0.52 of a cent to 99.12 cents US as Statistics Canada said that gross domestic product increased 0.2 per cent in October following a 0.1 per cent decline in September. Mining and oil and gas extraction were the main sources of growth.</p><p>But the showing was less than the 0.3 per cent rise that economists had expected as manufacturing decreased 0.6 per cent in October.</p><p>Manufacturers of non-durable goods cut back production by 2.3 per cent while those of durable goods increased their output by 0.8 per cent as production of motor vehicles and associated parts increased.</p><p>The loonie was supported by oil prices which shook off early losses as the February crude contract on the New York Mercantile Exchange gained $1.03 to US$91.51 a barrel, a day after crude closed above US$90 a barrel for the first time since October 2008.</p><p>The March copper contract on the Nymex moved down two cents to US$4.26 a pound after hitting a record closing high earlier in the week. Gold also moved lower with the February bullion contract on the Nymex down $6.90 at US$1,380.50 an ounce.</p><p>On the American economic front, orders for durable goods declined by a larger than expected 1.3 per cent in November, led by transportation equipment orders. Economists had expected a dip of 0.5 per cent. The U.S. Commerce Department reported that excluding transportation, durable goods orders rose by 2.4 per cent.</p><p>The U.S. government also reported that consumers increased their spending 0.4 per cent in November. The gain came after shoppers had ratcheted up spending by 0.7 per cent in October, the most since August 2009.</p><p>And slightly fewer Americans applied for unemployment benefits last week, the second drop in three weeks and a sign the job market is slowly healing. The U.S. Labour Department said the number of people seeking benefits edged down by 3,000 to a seasonally adjusted 420,000 in the week ended Dec. 18.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Chalk River reactor to be shut down for 33 days for maintenance and inspection</title><link>http://www.canadianbusiness.com/markets/headline_news/article.jsp?content=b5486109</link><description><![CDATA[OTTAWA - The troubled Chalk River nuclear reactor that produces medical isotopes will be shut down for 33 days in May to perform routine maintenance]]></description><author>The Canadian Press</author><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 16:21:00 -0400</pubDate><guid></guid><category>Market News</category><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>OTTAWA - The troubled Chalk River nuclear reactor that produces medical isotopes will be shut down for 33 days in May to perform routine maintenance and an inspection of the reactor.</p><p>The Chalk River National Research Universal reactor restarted producing isotopes in August after it was shut down for more than a year because of a pinhole-size radioactive water leak.</p><p>Atomic Energy of Canada Ltd. spokeswoman Robin Forbes said Thursday the reactor is regularly shut down for five-day periods for maintenance on roughly a monthly basis, but some of the work needed to be done will take longer than that.</p><p>"We want to do an extended outage to perform these planned maintenance activities that require a bit longer time," Forbes said Thursday.</p><p>Forbes also said a full vessel inspection will be done, a condition of its operating license.</p><p>MDS Nordion (TSX:MDS), a global supplier of radioactive materials used for medical imaging procedures around the world, relies on the reactor for its isotopes.</p><p>The company signed a deal in September with JSC Isotope, a subsidiary of Russia's state-owned RosAtom State Corp., to provide it with a supplemental supply of Molybdenum-99, used to make isotopes for about 80 per cent of nuclear medicine procedures.</p><p>MDS Nordion said Thursday the first sample of the isotope has been shipped from its Russian partner.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Canadian dollar closed at 99.12 cents US on Thursday, up 0.52 of a cent</title><link>http://www.canadianbusiness.com/markets/headline_news/article.jsp?content=c5486194</link><description><![CDATA[TORONTO - The Canadian dollar closed at 99.12 cents US on Thursday, up 0.52 of a cent.The U.S. dollar stood at C$1.0089, down 0.53 of]]></description><author>The Canadian Press</author><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 16:17:00 -0400</pubDate><guid></guid><category>Market News</category><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>TORONTO - The Canadian dollar closed at 99.12 cents US on Thursday, up 0.52 of a cent.</p><p>The U.S. dollar stood at C$1.0089, down 0.53 of a cent.</p><p>Pound sterling closed at C$1.5567, down 0.40 of a cent, and US$1.5430, up 0.42 of a cent.</p><p>The euro was worth C$1.3338, up 0.53 of a cent.</p><p>Quotations provided by BMO Capital Markets.</p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>